Hey there and welcome. Do you ever get stuck
こんにちは、ようこそ。英語で簡単な質問を するのに困ったことはありませんか？
when you're trying to ask a simple question in English?
心配しないで、誰にでも起こることです。
Oh, don't worry, it happens to literally everyone.
今日は、たくさんの質問をするための 簡単なコツを教えます。
But today I'm gonna show you one simple trick
実際、とても楽しいですよ。
that will let you ask tons of questions. And it's actually really fun.
さあ、始めましょう。お腹は空いていますか？
Okay, let's get right into it. Are you hungry?
この質問はよく聞きますよね？
You probably hear this question all the time, right?
あるいは、自分が聞きたいかもしれません。
Or maybe you wanna ask it.
では、数分後には
Well, what if I told you that in just a few minutes
このような質問を自分で作れるように なるとしたらどうでしょう？
you'll know exactly how to build questions
一緒にやってみましょう。
just like this one all by yourself?
思ったより簡単ですから。
Stick with me, because it is way easier than you think. You'll see.
要は、シンプルな動きに集約されます。
So it all comes down to one simple move.
これは、英語の質問を解放する 秘密の鍵のようなものです。
You can think of it like a secret key that unlocks,
準備はいいですか？
I mean, hundreds of English questions.
まず、このスライドにある シンプルな考えから始めましょう。
Are you ready to find out what it is?
英語は楽しい。そう思いませんか？
Okay, let's start with this simple thought you see on the slide.
これを質問にするにはどうすればいいでしょう？
English is fun. I really hope you agree with that.
例えば、誰かにそれが楽しいか 尋ねるには？
But how do we turn this into a question?
今、考えてみましょう。
Like, how could you ask someone if they think it's fun?
大きな秘密はB動詞にあります。
Hmm, let's figure that out right now.
この小さな言葉は小さいですが、 とても強力です。
And here it is, the big secret is all about the B verb.
これからその大きな動きを見ていきます。
This little word is small, but it is so powerful.
正直、この一つのコツが全てを 変えます。
And we are about to see its big move in action.
では、簡単な三ステップのレシピを 紹介します。
Honestly, this one trick changes everything. So here's the deal.
質問をするための超簡単な方法です。
It's just a simple three-step recipe for asking questions, super easy.
ステップ1、B動詞を見つけます。
Step one, you find the B verb.
am、is、areのような言葉です。
We're talking about words like am, is, or are.
ステップ2、その動詞を前に 移動させます。
Step two, you take that little verb
ステップ3、最後に 疑問符を付けます。
and just slide it all the way to the front.
これで完了です。
And step three, you pop a question mark right on the end.
さて、ここで重要なことが 2つあります。
And that's it, that's the whole recipe.
まず、疑問符を忘れずに 追加してください。
Now hang on, here are two super important things
これは、質問していることを 示す公式なサインです。
that people sometimes forget, so listen up.
次に、実際に声に出すときは、 最後に少し声を上げてください。
First, you have got to add that question mark.
「あなたは幸せですか？」ではなく、 「あなたは幸せですか？」です。
It's like the official signal that you're asking something.
その声の上がり方はイントネーションと 呼ばれ、
And second, when you actually say it out loud,
本当に重要です。さて、話はこれくらいにして、
let your voice go up a little bit at the end.
この秘密を試してみましょう。
Not are you happy, but more like are you happy?
いくつかの文を質問に変えて、 一緒にやってみます。
That little lift in your voice, it's called intonation
私たちの三ステップルールが 毎回完璧に機能するのを見てください。
and it's a real game changer. Okay, enough talk, right?
では、最初の文です。
Let's put this secret to the test.
「私は映画に遅れています」と 考えているとしましょう。
We're going to take some statements and turn them into questions and we'll do it together.
私たちのレシピに従って、 最初に何をする必要がありますか？
Just watch how our little three-step rule works perfectly every single time.
B動詞を見つける必要があります。 スライドで見つけられますか？
Alright, first one up.
はい、動詞は「am」です。
Imagine you're thinking, I am late for the movie.
それを前に移動させ、 疑問符を付けます。
According to our recipe, what's the very first thing we have to do?
「私は映画に遅れていますか？」 簡単でしたね？
We need to find that B verb. Can you spot it on the slide?
素晴らしい！最初の質問は成功です！
Yes, the verb is am.
次の文に行きましょう。 「あなたは幸せです」。
So we just move it to the front, add our question mark, and voila!
さて、あなたの番です。 この文のB動詞は何で、どこに移動させますか？
Am I late for the movie? See how easy that was?
考える時間をあげます。
Let's try another one. Here we have, you are happy.
素晴らしい！本当にコツをつかんできましたね。 続けましょう。
Okay, it's your turn. What's the B verb in this sentence, and where does it need to go?
では、他の誰かについて話すときは？ 「彼女はオーストラリア出身です」。
I'll give you a second to think about it.
この秘密のルールはまだ通用しますか？ もちろんです。
You got it. The verb is R, so it moves right to the front, and we get, are you happy?
ルールは誰にでも同じです。 例外はありません。
Excellent. See? You are really getting the hang of this. Let's keep this going.
その通り。ここでのB動詞は「is」です。 それを前に移動させて、
Okay, now what if we're talking about somebody else? Like, she is from Australia.
「彼女はオーストラリア出身ですか？」と 聞きます。
Perfect. You are becoming a total pro at this, I'm telling you.
完璧です。あなたはこれに完全に慣れてきましたね。
Okay, how about one last practice round?
では、最後の練習をしましょうか？
This time, we're talking about a group of people.
今回は人々のグループについてです。
They are good singers. You know exactly what to do now, right?
彼らは良い歌手です。もう何をすればいいか分かりますよね？
What's that B-verb's big move going to be?
そのB動詞の大事な動きは何でしょう？
And the answer is, are they good singers? Amazing.
答えは、彼らは良い歌手ですか？素晴らしい。
We just proved that our one simple rule works for I, you, she, and they.
私たちはこのシンプルなルールが、I、you、she、theyに通用することを証明しました。
It works for everybody. You basically have an English superpower now.
誰にでも使えます。あなたは今、英語のスーパーパワーを手に入れました。
Alright, you've seen the trick, you've practiced it.
さて、トリックを見て、練習しましたね。
it's time for a little challenge to test out your new superpower. Think of it like a quick, fun game.
新しいスーパーパワーを試すための小さなチャレンジの時間です。楽しいゲームのように考えてください。
You ready to play? Here we go. Your first challenge. Look at the words on the slide.
準備はいいですか？最初のチャレンジです。スライドの言葉を見てください。
They're all mixed up. Can you put them in the right order to make a question? Just remember
すべて混ざっています。質問を作るために正しい順番に並べられますか？覚えておいてください。
the number one rule. That B verb goes first. So, did you get it? The answer is, is she a student?
一番のルールは、そのB動詞が最初です。さて、分かりましたか？答えは、彼女は学生ですか？
If you figured that one out, great job. That was a pretty good one.
それが分かったなら、素晴らしい仕事です。なかなか良い問題でしたね。
Okay, challenge number 2. Let's keep that energy up. Unscramble these words into a question.
次はチャレンジ2です。エネルギーを保ちましょう。これらの言葉を質問に並べ替えてください。
We have FROM, ARE, THEY, JAPAN. You can totally do this.
FROM、ARE、THEY、JAPANがあります。あなたならできるはずです。
And the correct answer is...
正しい答えは…
Are they from Japan? Perfect. You totally passed the challenge. I knew you could do it.
彼らは日本出身ですか？完璧です。チャレンジに合格しましたね。できると思っていました。
And that's pretty much it. You've done it. I am officially declaring you a question master.
これでほぼ終わりです。あなたはやり遂げました。正式に質問マスターと宣言します。
faster. Let's just do a super quick review to make sure this new power sticks.
では、素早く復習して、この新しい力を定着させましょう。
So just take a look at the pattern on this slide. Whether you're talking about yourself
このスライドのパターンを見てください。自分を話すときはI am、
with I am, one other person with she is, or a whole group with they are, the pattern
他の人を話すときはshe is、グループを話すときはthey are、パターンは
is exactly the same every single time. That b-verb, whether it's am, is, or are, always
毎回全く同じです。そのB動詞は、am、is、areに関わらず、常に
always just moves to the front. It's so consistent.
前に移動します。とても一貫しています。
So if you remember just one thing from all of this, please let it be this. The one
このすべてから一つだけ覚えておいてほしいことがあります。それは、
One and only secret is to find that B verb and move it right to the front of the line.
唯一の秘密は、そのB動詞を見つけて、行の最前に移動させることです。
That's it. See? That wasn't so bad, was it?
それだけです。ほら、そんなに難しくなかったでしょう？
In fact, it was pretty easy.
実際、かなり簡単でした。
You now have a key that unlocks so many new conversations in English.
あなたは英語でたくさんの新しい会話を開く鍵を手に入れました。
So my final question for you is, now that you're a question master, what question
では、最後の質問です。あなたが質問マスターになった今、最初に何を聞きますか？
are you going to ask first? Go on, go try it out.
さあ、試してみてください。